www.propertypal.com

INTRODUCTION

This is the privacy notice or policy (notice) of PropertyPal.com Limited (we,

us or our).

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personaldata. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after yourpersonal data when you visit and use our website (regardless of where youvisit it from) http://www.PropertyPal.com (our website), whether as anestate agent, letting agent, property developer or property owner seekingto display a property you are marketing to users of our website interestedin viewing properties for sale or for rental, as an interested party seeking togather information shared by users of our website, or however otherwise.

It also informs you how we will look after your personal data when yougenerally interact with us as one of our customers, and about your privacyrights and how the law protects you. It does not cover any website youhave used to access our website or any website that you access from it.

This Policy also includes a series of disclosures in relation to and whichprovides more detail on the third-party service providers we partner with,the kinds of personal data they may gain access to, and what they do withit, including in our Cookie Policy, available at https://www.propertypal.com/cookie-policy.

It is important that you read this privacy notice so that you are fully awareof how and why we are using your data.

Please use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the termsused in this privacy notice.

1\. WHO WE ARE

Under the UK General Data Protection Regulation or the EU GeneralData Protection Regulation (collectively GDPR) and other relevant dataprotection legislation, we act as both a data controller (i.e. where wemake decisions) in relation to your personal data that we collect, as wellas a data processor (i.e. process data broadly in accordance with yourinstructions.

When we act as a Data Processor: When as a customer or user you useour services to process personal data, we act as a data processor. Underthese circumstances, the customer or user may act as a data controlleror data processor itself, and we will act as either a processor or a sub-processor.

When we act as a Data Controller: By contrast, when we collect personaldata and determine the purposes and means of processing that personaldata – for example, when we store account information for accountregistration, administration, services access, or contact information asexplained below – we act as a data controller.

Contact Details

Our full details are:

Full Name of Legal Entity: PropertyPal.com Limited, a companyincorporated in Northern Ireland under company number NI603400

Email Address: help@propertypal.com

Postal Address: Unit 2D Jennymount Business Park, North Derby Street,Belfast, BT15 3HN

ICO Registration Number: ZA128377 (this is the number under which weare registered with the ICO for the processing of personal data)

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information

Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data

protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate thechance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please

contact us in the first instance.

If you would like to make a complaint to the ICO, their contact details are:

By phone \- 0303 123 1113

Online \- https://ico.org.uk/concerns

Changes to the Privacy Notice and your Duty to Inform us of Changes

This version two of this Policy was last updated on Aug 2021 and historicversions can be obtained by contacting us.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate andcurrent. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes duringyour relationship with us.

Third-party Links

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins andapplications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections mayallow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not controlthese third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacystatements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read theprivacy notice of every website you visit.

2\. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an

individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include

data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data

about you which we have grouped together as set out below.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate andcurrent. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes duringyour relationship with us. Where you have registered to use our websiteyou can update your details or delete your account at any time.

DATA THAT YOU SUPPLY TO US

• General Personal Data \- This is personal information about you

that you share with us through filling in online or offline forms, by

email, through the post, on the telephone or by any other means.

Typically, when you visit, register or use the services on our website,as an ordinary user you will be asked to provide certain informationabout yourself, including your full name, email address, homeaddress and mobile phone number and other contact details, orcomments provided through our contact form.

Where you are an estate agent or property developer using thesite as a member, you will be asked to provide the above details,as well as your business name, bank account details for the purposesof administering your account, and addresses of properties that yousubmit.

If you provide verbal personal information that you give us consent

to use you will have such consent confirmed back to you in writing.

Where payment is made, additional personal information we ask youto supply may include your information needed to carry out anychecks, such as credit checks. We do not collect personal bankaccount details. If you apply for a role with our organisation, otherpersonal data shared is likely to include your employment history,

proof of identity, qualification checks, health information, or

whatever other information you volunteer to us.

You may also communicate your preferences in receiving marketingfrom us and our third parties and your communication preferences(including details you provide when you opt-in to receive marketingcommunications from us).

IMPORTANT NOTE

Unless submitted by the property owner or members of your socialnetwork, details held by us about a property do not comprise

personal data as defined by the GDPR. We may use the data held

about properties advertised to provide services to third parties.

We do not accept property listings directly from consumers, with theexception of registered members of a government approvedproperty redress scheme (including, in the Republic of Ireland, those

PRIVACY POLICY

www.propertypal.com

licensed by the Property Services Regulatory Authority). If you are theowner of a property being displayed for sale or for rent on ourwebsite this is because the agent you have chosen to use for the saleor the letting of your property has a contract with us to display thedetails of your property on our website and thereby place theinformation about your property fully in the public domain.

If the agent you have chosen to use for the sale or the letting of yourproperty has a contract with us and has not elected to display thedetails of your property on our website, you can request for suchdetails to be displayed via the agent.

• Marketing Data: You may also communicate your preferencesin receiving marketing from us and our third parties and yourcommunication preferences (including details you provide when youopt-in to receive marketing communications from us).

• Project Specific Personal Data: This also includes specific personal

data that we may gain technical access to (from you) through theservices that we provide for you, including where we host websitesor software solutions on your behalf, and can include numerous

different kinds of personal data, depending on the nature of the

databases or other information to which you grant us access. Wehave a separate data processing agreement that supplements thispolicy and which applies where we provide hosting services on yourbehalf.

If you provide verbal personal information that you give us consent

to use you will have such consent confirmed back to you in writing.

Where you are sharing personal data that does not directly relate toyou (e.g. your representatives that legally act on your behalf), youmust ensure you have the consent to do so and have shared thisNotice with that person/those people.

PERSONAL DATA THAT WE COLLECT

• Telephone Recordings \- Telephone conversations may be recordedto improve training and to ensure a high level of consistent customerservice.

• CCTV \- We may use CCTV cameras on our premises and may recordfootage of you where you attend our premises in person, and usesuch footage as required in our legitimate interests, including to

ensure the safety and well-being of our staff.

• Technical Data \- We may use the following technical services togather technical data as set out in our Cookie Policy from time totime, available at https://www.propertypal.com/cookie-policy.

INFORMATION WE RECEIVE FROM THIRD-PARTIES

• Business Partners \- where we have formal relationships withbusiness partners who may introduce new customers or salesopportunities to us, personal data would include personal contact

details, information on the areas of interest and data required to fulfil

a request, product or service. This would include referrals from estate

agents, personal referrals, and referrals from our affiliated company,

PropertyPal Mortgages Limited.

• Social Media \- where you have responded to a promotional item or

offer from us through social media facilities such as Facebook,

LinkedIn etc., we can receive profile information about you which can

include your name, address, telephone number(s) and/or yourbusiness contact details. This information would be used to respond

to your interest, to fulfil a request from you and/or to send you future

information and offers, where you have given clear consent to do so.

• Publicly Available Information \- we may collect personalinformation about you from publicly available sources. This caninclude your name, address and other publicly available information.As far as passible, we ensure that where any third-parties areinvolved in suppling such information, that they are compliant to doso. This may include credit reference agencies such as Experian orpublic registers such as the Companies House registry or theElectoral Register.

• Other \- from time to time, we may receive personal information fromother sources. We will always endeavour to ensure such informationis provided from reputable sources, who are GDPR compliant to do so.

We may also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical ordemographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived fromyour personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data

does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may

aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing

a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated

Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identifyyou, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used inaccordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you(including details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophicalbeliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade unionmembership, information about your health and genetic and biometricdata). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and

offences.

If you fail to provide personal data

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the termsof a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data whenrequested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or aretrying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with services).In this case, we may have to cancel a service you have with us but we willnotify you if this is the case at the time.

Cookies

A Cookie is a small text file that is added to your device’s hard drive by

a web server within our domain. Cookies cannot used to run softwareprograms or add a virus to your device. They are unique to you and avoidyou having to input the same information and preferences each time you

visit our web site(s). For more information on the cookies used by our

website, please see our Cookies Policy which is available at: https://www.propertypal.com/cookie-policy.

Our website’s servers automatically record ‘log files’ containing

information about the volume and characteristics of our website’s website

traffic (e.g. IP address, numbers of pages viewed, length of time spenton our website). Log files are used to build pictures of how our website

is used that help to monitor and improve the service provided by our

website. You cannot be identified from your log files.

3\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Mostcommonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

• Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into orhave entered into with you, for the purposes contemplated in anyseparate terms of use for our website that you have enteredinto, including for the purposes set out in the “Our Standard BusinessOperations” section below.• Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a thirdparty) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override thoseinterests.• Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing yourpersonal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketingcommunications to you via email or text message (which is somethingthat we do not typically do). If we do implement direct marketing in future,and you have consented to this, you have the right to withdraw consent tomarketing at any time by contacting us.

We may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground

depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Pleasecontact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying

on to process your personal data.

Our Standard Business Operations:

• To provide the services that we contract to do so with you;• To provide you with information that you request from us;• To confirm your identity as a natural living person; and

• As part of our billing, payments and recovery processes.

www.propertypal.com

Marketing

We may use your personal data to form a view on what we think you maywant or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide

which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this

marketing).

We will only send you specific property alerts using our Site in relation to

properties that you have subscribed to see.

You will only receive marketing communications from us if you have optedto receive it. This includes where you have consented to being contactedby us by email or telephone to discuss our products or services or otherrelated information.

We strive to provide you with choices regarding personal data uses formarketing and advertising and currently use E-Keeper (and will shortly be

migrating to SalesForce) to manage our email correspondence. You can

ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by followingthe opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by contactingus, as appropriate, at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will notapply to personal data provided to us as a result of a service purchase,service experience or other transactions.

Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collectedit, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reasonand that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to getan explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatiblewith the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notifyyou and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without yourknowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this isrequired or permitted by law.

Legal requirements

We will keep and use your data in terms of any legal or regulatoryrequirements that we have and can use your data to protect ourlegal position, if legal action is required, including the recovery of anyoutstanding debts.

By way of further example, we will share your personal data with therelevant agencies and without notice, where we are requested to orsuspect fraudulent activities, money laundering, terrorist related activities.

Enhancing our Services

We may use personal data (other than that comprised in private personaldata) for the purposes of providing, enhancing, or improving our services.

Website Administration and Customisation

We may use the information we collect about you for a variety of website

administration and customisation purposes. For example, we use your

information to process your registration request, provide you withservices and communications that you have requested, send you emailupdates and other communications, customise features and advertisingthat appear on our websites, deliver our websites content to you, measure

website traffic, measure user interests and traffic patterns, and improveour websites and the services and features offered via our websites.

Children under thirteen

Our website and services are not intended to be used by children under13 years old. We will never knowingly collect data from or on childrenbelow 13 years old. If you become aware of such a child (or anotherperson) supplying data on that child to us, please contact us.

4\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We may have to share your personal data with the categories of dataprocessors or data controllers set out below for the purposes set out inparagraph 4 above, or otherwise below.

General Disclosures

• with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our

ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section

1159 of the Companies Act 2006, or our affiliated companies,

including PropertyPal Mortgages Limited;

• with HM Revenue \& Customs, regulators and other authorities actingas processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom whorequire reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances;

• with anyone, where your data has been disclosed to us for thepurposes of public advertising on our website, on the basis outlinedabove;

• with third party purchasers, if we buy, sell or merge any businessor assets of our business and are required to share data as part ofthe buying, selling or merger agreement. or if our assets are acquiredby a third-party, and data is transferred as part of the purchasedassets. If any such change happens, we will ensure that it is under

terms that preserve the confidentiality of your personal data, and

we will notify you on our website or by email before any transfer ofyour personal data. Any purchaser would be bound by the terms ofthis notice as regards your data;

• with professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllersincluding lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in theEuropean Union or United Kingdom who provide consultancy,banking, legal, insurance and accounting services, where they have aneed to know same for any of the purposes set out above; or

• with reputable and trusted third-parties where we have asked themto contact you on our behalf, where you have given us consent, it ispart of our contractual agreement, is a legal requirement or there isclear legitimate interest between us(these services may includesending you email, calling you by telephone, sending you informationthrough the post etc); and

• with specific selected third parties, determined by us, if you breach

any agreement with us, including so as to enforce our rights against

you, including credit-reference agencies, debt-collection firms or

service providers, solicitors or barristers and law enforcementagencies (if applicable);

• with service providers acting as processors based in the EuropeanUnion or United Kingdom who provide IT and system administrationservices. Below we have set out a non-exhaustive list of the criticalthird-party services providers whose software and services we utilise,and with whom your account might otherwise interact, and a briefnote of how we use them.

• Email Marketing Providers: We may use your personal data inmarketing communications, as noted above, and collaborate withe-mail marketing services providers, e.g. Mailchimp to manage andsend e-mails to you, where you have opted in to receiving them. Youcan unsubscribe directly from any mailing list using the unsubscribelinks provided within emails.

• Payment Processors: We may use third-party services for paymentprocessing (e.g. payment processors) or payment analytics, forexample, Stripe. Any payment processor we use will adhere tothe standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security

Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa,

Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirementshelp ensure the secure handling of payment information.

• Remarketing Providers: We use third-party vendors’ remarketingservices to advertise on third-party websites to you after visitingour website(s). These third-party vendors collect information aboutyour activity on our website to enable us to: (a) measure and

analyse traffic and browsing activity on our site; (b) show

advertisements for our products or services to you on third-partywebsites; (c) measure and analyse the performance of ouradvertising campaigns.

Some third-party vendors may use non-cookie technologies that maynot be impacted by browser settings that block cookies. Your browsermay not permit you to stop such technologies. You can use the

www.propertypal.com

following third-party tools to decline the collection and use ofinformation to serve you interest-based advertising:

a. The NAI’s opt-out platform: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/b. The EDAA’s opt-out platform http://www.youronlinechoices.com/c. The DAA’s opt-out platform: http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2\&lang=EN

We may share information, such as hashed e-mail addresses (if

available) or other online identifiers collected on our website with

these third-party vendors. This identification allows these third-party

vendors to recognise and deliver ads to you across devices andbrowsers. To read more about the technologies used by thesethird-party vendors and their cross-device capabilities, please refer tothe Privacy Policy of each vendor.

• Hosting \& Backend Infrastructure: We use this type of serviceto host data and provide the Service. These are protected bystandard authentication and authorisation provided elsewhere.

• Infrastructure Monitoring: We use this type of service tomonitor our applications and the site, to detect issues with andmeasure performance, operation, uptime, maintenance, and usage.The personal data that is processed depends upon theimplementation of these services and may include log centralisationand application usage.

• Customer Feedback and Support Management: We use thistype of service to manage any customer feedback and support,including feature requests and roadmap insights. The personal data

processed depends on what is offered by you when using the site.

• Service Applications: We also use third-party service providersto better our services, including reCAPTCHA, an invisible captchaservice operated by Google, Inc. The reCAPTCHA service may collectinformation from you and your Device for security purposes.

• Analytical Service Applications: We may share appropriate

information with providers in order to analyse our website traffic to

improve products and services.

• Support Platform: We may share information with our support

platform provider, SalesForce, where you contact us via social media

or via our helpdesk email, and a record is created in of your email

address, name or social media profile name, to see a history of

contact between you and our support team.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal dataand to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-partyservice providers to use your personal data for their own purposes andonly permit them to process the minimal personal data required for

specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions. We may also

share personal data with your permission, so we can perform services youhave requested, or use it in other ways you may have authorised.

We do not share, sell, rent, or trade personal data with third parties fortheir commercial purposes.

Third-party marketing

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal

data with any company outside of our own (or our affiliated companies)

for marketing purposes.

If you have consented, we may provide your information to carefullyscreened third parties for the purposes detailed above, includingadvertisers, estate agents and advertising networks that require thedata to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not

disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers,

but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users(for example, we may inform them that 500 men aged under 30 haveclicked on their advertisement on any given day). We may also use suchaggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience theywant to target (for example, women in BT1). We may make use of thepersonal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply withour advertisers’ wishes by displaying their advertisement to that targetaudience.

5\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

The EEA, UK and other countries outside the EEA and the UK have

differing data protection laws, some of which may provide lower levels of

protection of privacy.

It is sometimes necessary for us to share your personal data to countriesoutside the UK and EEA. In those cases we will comply with applicable UKand EEA laws designed to ensure the privacy of your personal data (forexample by putting in place model clauses designed to secure the privacy

of your personal data). For example, we will transfer your personal data to

Asana and Google Drive, providers of third-party software services to us,who are located in the USA.

As we are based in the UK we will also transfer your personal data fromthe EEA (where you are based in the EEA) to the UK.

We will also ensure all protections required by applicable UK and EEA lawsare in place before transferring personal data to any organisation or body(or its subordinate bodies) governed by public international law or setup by, or on the basis of, an agreement between two or more countries(international organisations). We may transfer your personal data to thefollowing international organisations insert.

Under data protection laws, we can only transfer your personal data to acountry outside the UK/EEA or to an international organisation where:

• in the case of transfers subject to UK data protection law, the UKgovernment has decided the particular country ensures anadequate level of protection of personal data (known as an‘adequacy regulation’) further to Article 45 of the UK GDPR;

• in the case of transfers subject to EEA data protection laws, theEuropean Commission has decided that the particular countryensures an adequate level of protection of personal data (known asan ‘adequacy decision’) further to Article 45 of the EU GDPR;

• there are appropriate safeguards in place, together with enforceable

rights and effective legal remedies for you; or

• a specific exception applies under relevant data protection law.

Where we transfer your personal data outside the UK we do so on thebasis of an adequacy regulation or (where such is not available) insert, e.g.legally-approved standard data protection clauses recognised or issuedfurther to Article 46(2) of the UK GDPR. In the event we cannot or choosenot to continue to rely on either of those mechanisms at any time we willnot transfer your personal data outside the UK unless we can do so onthe basis of an alternative mechanism or exception provided by UK dataprotection law.

Where we transfer your personal data outside the EEA we do so on thebasis of the UK interim bridge or an adequacy decision or (where suchis not available) insert, e.g. legally-approved standard data protectionclauses issued further to Article 46(2) of the EU GDPR. In the event wecannot or choose not to continue to rely on either of those mechanisms atany time we will not transfer your personal data outside the EEA unless wecan do so on the basis of an alternative mechanism or exception providedby applicable data protection law.

Any changes to the destinations to which we send personal data or in thetransfer mechanisms we use to transfer personal data internationally will

be notified to you in accordance with the Section 10 on ‘Changes to this

Notice’ below.

6\. DATA SECURITY

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent yourpersonal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in anunauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access toyour personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and otherthird parties who have a business need to know. They will only processyour personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of

confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal databreach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach wherewe are legally required to do so.

www.propertypal.com

No method of transmission, or method of electronic storage, is 100%secure. Although we will take all reasonable measures to protect yourpersonal data, we cannot guarantee its security. Any transmission is atyour own risk.

7\. DATA RETENTION

How long will you use my Personal Data for?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the

purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying anylegal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, weconsider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, thepotential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of yourpersonal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data andwhether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and theapplicable legal requirements.

We will keep your personal data for the term you have consented to, thecontracted term between us where there is a legitimate interest for us toremain in contact with you, or for the legally required period, whichever isthe longest.

By law we have to keep basic information about any of our customers

(including contact, identity, financial and transaction data) for six years

after you cease being a customer for tax purposes.

CHANGING THE INFORMATION HELD

Registered members of our website can update their information, changesettings or cancel their membership at any time to ensure that suchinformation is accurate and kept up-to-date.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data - see Section 8below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that itcan no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes

in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further

notice to you.

No fee usually required

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exerciseany of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if yourrequest is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we mayrefuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm

your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or toexercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure thatpersonal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation toyour request to speed up our response.

Time limit to respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month.Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request isparticularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case,we will notify you and keep you updated.

8\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection lawsin relation to your personal data. You have the right to:

Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “datasubject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of thepersonal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfullyprocessing it.

Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. Thisenables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about youcorrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data youprovide to us.

Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us todelete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for uscontinuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete orremove your personal data where you have successfully exercised yourright to object to processing (see below), where we may have processedyour information unlawfully or where we are required to erase yourpersonal data to comply with local law.Generally, if requested whenever you cancel your membership, we willerase your data within three months of your request, subject to retentionof any data which we are required to keep for legal or regulatory reasons(as outlined above).

Please note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your

request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you,

if applicable, at the time of your request.

Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on alegitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something aboutyour particular situation which makes you want to object to processingon this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights andfreedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processingyour personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we maydemonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process yourinformation which override your rights and freedoms.

Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enablesyou to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in thefollowing scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b)where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it;(c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it asyou need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you haveobjected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we haveoverriding legitimate grounds to use it.

Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. Wewill provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal datain a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that thisright only applies to automated information which you initially providedconsent for us to use or where we used the information to perform acontract with you.

Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to

process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness

of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If youwithdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain productsor services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time youwithdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exerciseany of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if yourrequest is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we mayrefuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

Where you exercise one of your rights, we may need to request specificinformation from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your

right to exercise such rights. This is a security measure to ensure thatpersonal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation toyour request to speed up our response.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month.Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request isparticularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case,we will notify you and keep you updated.

9\. HOW DO YOU RESPOND TO COMPELLED DISCLOSUREREQUIREMENTS?

We may disclose personal data or other information we collect about youto law enforcement in response to a valid subpoena, court order, warrant,or similar governmental order, or when we believe in good faith thatdisclosure is reasonably necessary to protect our property or rights, orthose of third parties or the public at large.

In complying with court orders and similar legal processes, we strive for

www.propertypal.com

transparency. When permitted, we will make a reasonable effort to notify

users of any disclosure of their information, unless we are prohibited bylaw or court order from doing so, or in rare, exigent circumstances.

10\. LEGAL

Changes to this Notice

We may change this notice from time to time. Any material changes to this

notice will be notified to you.

Choice of Law and Jurisdiction

This notice shall be governed by and interpreted in accordance with thelaws of Northern Ireland and you irrevocably agree that the courts ofNorthern Ireland shall have exclusive jurisdiction to settle any disputewhich may arise out of, under, or in connection with this policy.

GLOSSARY

Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation

means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliancewith a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to

Personal Data

means any personal information we hold on you;

Performance of a Contract

means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance ofa contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request beforeentering into such a contract;

EEA

means European Economic Area;

GDPR

has the meaning given in Section 1;

ICO

means the Information Commissioner’s Office - the UK data protection

regulatory body;

Legitimate Interest

means the interest of our business in conducting and managing ourbusiness to enable us to give you the best service and the best and mostsecure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potentialimpact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before weprocess your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not useyour personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by theimpact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required orpermitted to by law);

Third party(ies)

refers to external suppliers who your personal data may be shared with;

We, us, our

means PropertyPal.com Limited;

You, your, data subject,

relates to you as a natural living person; and

Your representative

means someone or some people who legally acting on your behalf.
